♪When sorrow and joy blend into ink♪
♪عندما يمتزج الحزن والفرح في الحبر♪
♪Flowers fade, rain falls, helpless as time♪
تذبل الأزهار، ويهطل المطر، عاجزين كعجز الزمن.
♪Lament this frail body, tangled in love and hate♪
♪رثوا هذا الجسد الهزيل، المتشابك بين الحب والكراهية♪
♪Yet I still wrestle with fate♪
♪ومع ذلك ما زلتُ أصارع القدر♪
♪Snow drifts down, burying all glory♪
♪ يتساقط الثلج، فيدفن كل مجد ♪
♪Blame this destiny granted to me♪
♪ألوم هذا القدر الذي مُنح لي♪
♪Trapped in the chains of love and cause♪
♪محاصرون في قيود الحب والقضية♪
♪When the dust finally settles♪
♪عندما تهدأ الأمور أخيرًا♪
=Glory in Shadows=
=المجد في الظلال=
=Episode 19=
=الحلقة 19=
Father.
أب.
Escort Young Master Jingxu back to rest.
رافق السيد الشاب جينغشو إلى مكان الراحة.
- Yes.
- نعم.
You two think you can
أنتما تعتقدان أنكما تستطيعان
bring me down?
هل تريد أن تحبطني؟
It is far too early for such confidence, Old Madam.
من السابق لأوانه جداً أن نثق بهذا القدر من الثقة، سيدتي العجوز.
Once we find the Fan Scorpion Poison
بمجرد أن نجد سم عقرب المروحة
and prove you killed Qin Ruoyi,
وأثبت أنك قتلت تشين رويي،
no clever words will save you then.
لن تنقذك الكلمات الذكية حينها.
What Fan Scorpion Poison?
ما هو سم عقرب المروحة؟
I've never even heard of it.
لم أسمع به من قبل.
And I didn't kill her.
وأنا لم أقتلها.
I have nothing to fear.
ليس لدي ما أخشاه.
Even now, you're still hiding the truth.
حتى الآن، ما زلت تخفي الحقيقة.
Why would I need to hide anything?
لماذا أحتاج إلى إخفاء أي شيء؟
Just the two of you?
أنتما الاثنان فقط؟
Against me? Such arrogance.
ضدي؟ يا له من غرور!
Then what about me?
وماذا عني أنا؟
You...
أنت...
You're awake?
هل أنت مستيقظ؟
Brother,
أخ،
Father has awakened.
استيقظ الأب.
Is the case concluded?
هل انتهت القضية؟
You just woke up.
لقد استيقظت للتو.
How do you know?
كيف علمت بذلك؟
Wan'er told me everything.
أخبرني وانر بكل شيء.
Master, you've just woken up.
سيدي، لقد استيقظت للتو.
You haven't recovered...
لم تتعافَ بعد...
That's fine.
هذا جيّد.
I've been confined to this sickbed.
لقد لزمت الفراش بسبب المرض.
I've had quite enough of it.
لقد سئمت من هذا الأمر تماماً.
However,
لكن،
during all those years of my coma,
خلال كل تلك السنوات التي قضيتها في غيبوبتي،
I was not entirely unaware.
لم أكن غافلاً تماماً.
Today, at the Court of Judicial Review,
اليوم، في محكمة المراجعة القضائية،
you talked your way out of the charges.
لقد تمكنت من التخلص من التهم بالكلام.
Now you've returned to the Marquis Manor,
والآن بعد عودتك إلى قصر ماركيز،
I, as the Marquis,
أنا، بصفتي الماركيز،
will conduct my own trial.
سأجري محاكمتي بنفسي.
Zhao Qingru,
تشاو تشينغرو،
kneel.
اركع.
Kneel!
اركع!
You wretch,
يا لك من بائس!
how dare you collude with others
كيف تجرؤ على التواطؤ مع الآخرين؟
to harm the descendants of the Li family!
لإلحاق الأذى بأحفاد عائلة لي!
While I lay in a coma, you humiliated me again and again.
بينما كنتُ في غيبوبة، أهنتني مراراً وتكراراً.
Every single of these matters,
كل هذه الأمور،
others may not know,
قد لا يعلم الآخرون،
but I know them all!
لكنني أعرفهم جميعاً!
I was left unconscious for so long.
لقد بقيت فاقداً للوعي لفترة طويلة.
You were the one
أنت كنت الشخص
who poisoned me, weren't you?
من الذي سممني، أليس أنت؟
It was her!
كانت هي!
Your precious daughter found the poison for you!
ابنتك العزيزة وجدت السم من أجلك!
I did not.
لم أفعل.
Mother, why do you falsely accuse me?
يا أمي، لماذا تتهمينني زوراً؟
I've lived a sheltered life.
لقد عشت حياة منعزلة.
How could I know about poisons?
كيف لي أن أعرف عن السموم؟
Besides, Father treats me so kindly.
إضافة إلى ذلك، يعاملني والدي بلطف شديد.
He cherishes me deeply.
إنه يعتز بي كثيراً.
How could I ever harm him?
كيف لي أن أؤذيه؟
You deceitful girl!
يا لكِ من فتاة مخادعة!
I should have ended you!
كان يجب أن أقتلك!
Silence!
الصمت!
You wretch,
يا لك من بائس!
even now,
حتى الآن،
you're still trying to frame Wan'er!
ما زلت تحاول توريط وانر!
Do you think that while I was in a coma,
هل تعتقد أنه بينما كنت في غيبوبة،
I couldn't hear what you said
لم أستطع سماع ما قلته
or know what you did?
أو هل تعلم ماذا فعلت؟
Open your eyes and look clearly!
افتح عينيك وانظر بوضوح!
How dare you humiliate me like this!
كيف تجرؤ على إذلالي هكذا!
If you truly could hear,
لو كنت تستطيع أن تسمع حقاً،
then you should know
إذن يجب أن تعرف
why I did what I did!
لماذا فعلت ما فعلت!
We've been married for so many years,
لقد تزوجنا لسنوات عديدة،
why do you still resent me so deeply?
لماذا ما زلت تحمل لي ضغينة عميقة؟
Is it all because of Jingchuan and Yan?
هل كل ذلك بسبب جينغتشوان ويان؟
So many years have passed,
لقد مرت سنوات عديدة،
yet you still can't let it go?
لكنك ما زلت غير قادر على التخلي عنه؟
How easily those words escape your lips.
كم هي سهلة أن تخرج تلك الكلمات من شفتيك.
But they've haunted me every sleepless night!
لكنهم ظلوا يطاردونني في كل ليلة بلا نوم!
Back then, I defied my father's objections
في ذلك الوقت، تحديت اعتراضات والدي.
and insisted on marrying you.
وأصر على الزواج منك.
I was a fool to believe you.
كنتُ أحمقاً عندما صدقتك.
You promised me a lifetime of devotion.
لقد وعدتني بإخلاص مدى الحياة.
But in the end,
لكن في النهاية،
I was the one left behind.
لقد كنت أنا من تُرك في الخلف.
It was all because of that woman!
كان كل ذلك بسبب تلك المرأة!
We hadn't even been married two years
لم نكن قد تزوجنا حتى عامين
when she came straight to my door with that jerk!
عندما أتت مباشرة إلى باب منزلي مع ذلك الأحمق!
Everyone in the capital knew.
كان الجميع في العاصمة يعلمون بذلك.
She turned me into a laughingstock!
لقد حولتني إلى أضحوكة!
Don't you dare mention my mother.
إياك أن تذكر أمي.
Who would have known
من كان ليعلم؟
that woman died the very next year,
توفيت تلك المرأة في العام التالي مباشرة.
leaving behind her son
تاركة وراءها ابنها
who outshone my own at every turn.
الذين تفوقوا على أمثالي في كل منعطف.
How could I possibly accept that?
كيف لي أن أقبل بذلك؟
As the matriarch,
بصفتها الأم الكبرى،
you were expected to be magnanimous
كان من المتوقع أن تكون كريماً.
and treat concubines' children kindly.
وعاملوا أبناء الجواري معاملة حسنة.
This title of matriarch
هذا اللقب الخاص بالأم الكبرى
has weighed on me my whole life!
لقد أثقل كاهلي طوال حياتي!
Why must I be forgiving?
لماذا يجب عليّ أن أكون متسامحاً؟
Why must I be magnanimous?
لماذا يجب أن أكون كريماً؟
I refuse!
أرفض!
I want everyone who stand in my son's way
أريد أن أساعد كل من يقف في طريق ابني
to die!
أن أموت!
Zhao Qingru.
تشاو تشينغرو.
Zhao Qingru,
تشاو تشينغرو،
you are no longer fit to be the matriarch.
لم تعد مؤهلة لتكوني ربة الأسرة.
For your years presiding over this household,
تقديراً لسنوات رئاستكم لهذا المنزل،
you will be told to have succumbed to a sudden illness.
سيُقال لك إنك قد توفيت بسبب مرض مفاجئ.
You'll spend the rest of your days
ستقضي بقية أيامك
in the back courtyard.
في الفناء الخلفي.
No.
لا.
Master! Master!
يا سيدي! يا سيدي!
I can give up the title of matriarch,
يمكنني التخلي عن لقب الأم الكبرى،
but Xu'er...
لكن شوير...
Xu'er is your legitimate son.
شو إير هو ابنك الشرعي.
He must inherit your title.
يجب أن يرث لقبك.
It must go to Xu'er,
يجب أن يذهب إلى شو إير،
- not your eldest son! - Let go!
- ليس ابنك الأكبر! - اتركه!
I am not dead yet.
أنا لم أمت بعد.
I still rule this household!
ما زلتُ أُسيطر على هذا المنزل!
No.
لا.
Xu'er is your legitimate son.
شو إير هو ابنك الشرعي.
He must inherit the title.
يجب أن يرث اللقب.
I'll kill you.
سأقتلك.
- I'll kill you. - Guards!
- سأقتلك. - أيها الحراس!
Take her away!
خذوها بعيداً!
I'll kill you.
سأقتلك.
- Take her away! - Let me go!
- خذوها بعيداً! - دعوني أذهب!
I'll kill you.
سأقتلك.
My Xu'er is the rightful heir!
ابنتي شو إير هي الوريثة الشرعية!
My Xu'er must inherit the title!
يجب أن ترث ابنتي شو إير اللقب!
I'll kill you.
سأقتلك.
- My son is the heir! - Announce her death!
- ابني هو الوريث! - أعلنوا وفاتها!
Wan'er.
وانير.
Father.
أب.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Sit by my side.
اجلس بجانبي.
My Wan'er has grown up.
لقد كبر ابني وانير.
You've become more lovely and graceful.
لقد أصبحتِ أكثر جمالاً ورقة.
Thanks for your concern, Father.
شكراً لاهتمامك يا أبي.
During all the years I was in a coma,
خلال كل السنوات التي قضيتها في غيبوبة،
you rarely came to see me.
نادرًا ما كنت تأتي لرؤيتي.
I feared angering Mother,
كنت أخشى إغضاب أمي،
so I dared not visit you.
لذلك لم أجرؤ على زيارتك.
That no longer matters.
لم يعد ذلك مهماً.
That wretch is gone for good.
لقد رحل ذلك الوغد إلى الأبد.
From now on, you can stay by my side every day.
من الآن فصاعدًا، يمكنك البقاء بجانبي كل يوم.
My Lady,
سيدتي،
you've rubbed it red.
لقد فركتها حتى احمرّت.
Leave.
يترك.
- My lady... - Go!
- سيدتي... - انطلقي!
Why is it me?
لماذا أنا بالذات؟
♪This life, like foam♪
♪هذه الحياة، مثل الزبد♪
♪The wind is bleak, leaving me alone♪
♪الريح عاتية، تتركني وحيداً♪
♪New snow falls thick beneath the eaves♪
♪يتساقط الثلج الجديد بكثافة تحت حواف السقف♪
♪Covering the courtyard gate♪
♪تغطية بوابة الفناء♪
♪Your gaze melts winter into spring♪
♪نظرتك تذيب الشتاء في الربيع♪
♪Turning back from the boundless multitude♪
♪العودة من بين الجموع التي لا حدود لها♪
♪Gazing at you in that fleeting moment♪
♪أنظر إليك في تلك اللحظة العابرة♪
♪All the hardships fade into drifting dust♪
♪تتلاشى كل المصاعب في غبار متناثر♪
♪A foolish dream turns earnest with you in it♪
♪حلمٌ ساذجٌ يتحول إلى حلمٍ جادٍّ بوجودك فيه♪
♪Even a feigned play can grow into true affection♪
♪حتى التمثيل المصطنع يمكن أن يتحول إلى عاطفة حقيقية♪
♪Too many dusks walked alone beneath my umbrella♪
♪كثير من الغسقات سارت وحيدة تحت مظلتي♪
♪Yet I crave the warmth left in your embrace♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى الدفء المتبقي في حضنك♪
♪Among thousands of bright lamps, is there one♪
♪من بين آلاف المصابيح الساطعة، هل يوجد واحد؟♪
♪That waits quietly for me?♪
♪هل ينتظرني بصمت؟♪
♪Time grinds through the rings of memory♪
♪ يمر الوقت سريعاً عبر حلقات الذاكرة ♪
♪Only you keep me warm in the long night♪
♪أنتِ وحدكِ من تُدفئينني في الليل الطويل♪
♪Scars left by the days gone by♪
♪ندوبٌ خلّفتها الأيام الخوالي♪
♪Lie upon the lines of our hands together♪
♪استلقوا على خطوط أيدينا معًا♪
♪I hold out a heart sincere and true♪
♪أُخرج قلباً صادقاً وحقيقياً♪
♪Crossing the deep courtyard♪
♪عبور الفناء العميق♪
♪Just to trade it for one kiss from you♪
♪فقط لأستبدلها بقبلة واحدة منك♪
♪Praying our hair turns gray without regret♪
♪ندعو أن يتحول شعرنا إلى اللون الرمادي دون ندم♪
♪So that true love will finally come to be♪
♪حتى يتحقق الحب الحقيقي في النهاية♪